npu.edu 2018-05-11

# NPU Website Privacy Policy | Northwestern Polytechnic University

**PRIVACY POLICY**

  Date Effective: May 3rd, 2016

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we may collect from you when you visit our websites, access our services, participate in our programs, or otherwise interact with us. It also describes how we use and disclose the information we collect, how we protect information from unauthorized use or disclosure, and the choices you have regarding our collection and use of such information.

**CONSENT TO PRIVACY POLICY**  
By accessing our website to obtain information or services or by providing solicited or unsolicited personal information to us online, you are consenting to our use of such information, subject to applicable laws, and agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**  
We may collect and use your personal and other information for research, public service, or teaching programs, for administrative purposes, to administer services, for future communication, or to improve the user experience of or troubleshoot issues with our site. We define the term “personal information” to mean any information that we directly associate with, or use to identify, a specific person. This may include information such as your name, phone number, address, social security or tax identification number, email address, a user name or other online registration information, and a financial account or credit card number. Such personal information may be requested for research, public service, or teaching programs, or for administrative purposes. Some personal information, such as credit card account information, may be requested for purchases or enrollment. Examples of other information that we automatically collect include IP addresses and browser and computer types.

  **DISCLOSURE OF COLLECTED INFORMATION**  
Generally, NPU will not disclose, without your consent, personal information collected about you, except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

  We may enter into relationships with third parties that provide services (e.g., credit card processing, website enhancements, insurance, and transportation). In such circumstance, we disclose personal information that is necessary for such service providers to perform such services.

  We may disclose your personal information to legal, government, regulatory, or accrediting authorities; in response to subpoenas, court orders, or when otherwise required by law; to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; if we determine disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action against illegal, illicit, or dangerous activities; or if we determine its disclosure is necessary in an emergency.

  **COOKIES, WEB BEACONS AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES.**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You may opt out of the aggregation and analysis of data collected about you on our website by Google Analytics by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> and downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

  **HOW WE RESPOND TO DO NOT TRACK SIGNALS**  
Currently, our web servers do not recognize or respond to “Do Not Track” signals. Our website may continue to collect information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. 

  **CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**  
NPU's website is not intended for children under the age of 13 and there are no areas specifically set aside for children under age 13. Nonetheless, we recognize that the NPU's website may be of general interest to all audiences and we therefore encourage parents to assist their children if they intend to explore our website.

**ACCESS TO AND RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
You may make changes to some of your personal information through the applicable user portal. We may keep a record of changes (including deletions) and disclose them for lawful purposes. We keep your personal information for as long as we think is necessary or advisable, and we reserve the right to retain it to the full extent not prohibited by law. If you are an applicant or student, you may also review your personal information that is readily accessible or request that it be updated by contacting Student Services.

**SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We use various physical, electronic, and procedural measures designed to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse. However, because no data security systems are completely secure, we do not warrant that any personal information that you provide to us will be secure or safe from unauthorized access. If you provide any personal information to us, you do so at your own risk. 

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**  
For your information and convenience, our website may contain links to websites operated by third parties. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, the practices of third parties that collect your personal information. Each of these linked websites may maintain its own policies about the collection, use, and protection of your personal information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of such third parties to learn about their information practices and security measures. 

  **CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**  
We will modify this Privacy Policy if our practices change. We will notify you of such changes by posting the modified version on our website and indicating the date it was last modified. Any updated version of this Privacy Policy will be effective as of the date at the top of this page. We encourage you to visit our website periodically to view the latest version of this Privacy Policy.
